Reed-Prentice Corporation Collection
Reed-Prentice Corporation Collection
1940-1968
National Plastics Center & Museum.
3 folders
Collection consists of copies of drawings and an instruction book concerning Reed-Prentice Corporation’s 10D-6 & 10D-8 plastic injection molding machine containing parts by Vickers.
2663675
Biographical History
Reed-Prentice Corporation is a manufacturer of injection molding machines, based in West Springfield, Massachusetts.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Reed-Prentice Corporation Collection consists of copies of drawings and an instruction book concerning Reed-Prentice Corporation’s 10D-6 & 10D-8 plastic injection molding machine containing parts by Vickers.
Arrangement of the Collection
Arranged into series by format.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; Reed-Prentice Ltd.; Vickers, Inc.; Plastics industry and trade.; Injection molding of plastics.; Plastics machinery.; Technical drawings.; Brochures.; Diagrams.; Manuals (instructional materials); Die plates.; Chemical engineers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008.
Inventory
- Printed material
  - Instruction manual for the Reed-Prentice 10D-6 and 10D-8 plastic injection molding machine (Box 1)
  - Vickers, Inc. brochures, 1948-1968; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Brochure for Reed-Prentice Plastic Injection Molding Machines, including 10D 6-8 oz., 1940 (Box 1)
- Drawings
  - Wiring diagram for 10A & 10D Plastic Machine, 1942-1944; copy stamped 1951; 22 x28.5" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Wiring diagram for 10A 2/4 & 10D 6/8 Thermoplastic machine, 1941; 22 x 34.5" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Wiring diagram, 1945; 28 x 38" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Hydraulic circuit for 10D 8 plastic injection mold machine, 1953; 18 x 24" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Wiring diagram auto control panel with sliding safety drawer on 10D 6 & 8 Thermoplastic Machine, 1940; copy stamp 1952; 17 x 22" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - [unlabelled], 14 x 22" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Movable die plate thrust shoe, links & die plates used on Thermoplastic Machine 10A 2-4 & 10D 6-8, 1941-1944; 11 x 17.5" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Front link thrust shoe on links & die plates for 10A 2-4, 10D 6-8 plastic machine, 1942-1944; 9 x 10.5" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)
  - Front link thrust shoe on links & die plates for 10A 2-4, 10D 6-8 plastic machine, 1941-1944; 8.5 x 11" (Map-case 1, Drawer 97)